Guide to the Scot Borofsky Papers, 1982-2007 MSS.346
Fales Library and Special Collections
Scot Borofsky Papers
1982-2007
Fales Library and Special Collections
Borofsky, Scot, b. 1957
MSS.346
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Scot Borofsky is a grafitti, studio, and commercial artist. This small collection documents his career in New York City and other places his artwork has been shown.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series:
Missing Title
Series I: Catalogs
Series II: Portfolio
Series III: Media
Series I is arranged chronologically. Series II is in the original order in which it was organized in Scot Borofsky's portfolio.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Provenance
The collection was donated to the Fales Library by Scot Borofsky in 2012.
Biographical Note
Born in Brattleboro, Vermont, Scot Borofsky graduated from Rhode Island School of Design and Painting in 1981, and received a Max Beckman Painting Scholarship at The Brooklyn Museum where he worked for one year. Borofsky first achieved notoriety in the New York art world for his 25 spray paintings made in the East Village during the early 80s, and from the subsequent spray paintings that were shown at the Mokotoff Gallery during the remainder of that decade. The artist left New York to return to his native Vermont in 1991. During the 90s, besides raising two boys, organic farming, and working in various fields of specialized construction, Borofsky nurtured his "graffiti symbols" into a mature style of oil painting.
- Coolgrove.com, Undated. Retreived from
Scope and Content
This collection contains papers that document Scot Borofsky's career as a graffiti and studio artist. It includes catalogs, programs, and promotion cards from exhibits, articles about Borofsky's art, and a video cassette of a movie in which Borofsky's art is featured.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Painters |y United States; Graffiti artists; Street art |z New York (state) |z New York |y 20th century; Borofsky, Scot, b. 1957
- Series I: Catalogs
  - "Scot Borofsky: Thoughtwork" - Mokotoff Gallery catalog, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Scot Borofsky: Paintings" - Mokotoff Gallery catalog, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Studio in the Street; Street in the Studio" - Battleboro Museum and Arts Center catalog, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Portfolio
  - Binding design and business card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Map of Alphabet City and Pattern Walk, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photos and catalogs from "Seven from the Street in their Studios", Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Scot Borofsky: Thoughtwork" exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Lower East Side Polygon: Street in the Cellar" at Danceteria - exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Blast" zine - January and February, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tropical Rain Forest: Benefit Exhibit for Green Ink, Inc." poster, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Picture and article about Borofsky in the Village Voice, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Contemporary Primitive - show at ABC No Rio - exhibit cards and East Village Eye article, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs from unidentified group exhibit, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Manhattan Tenochtitlan - exhibit program, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Illuminations: The Art of Our Future" group exhibit at Palladium - program, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "New, Used and Improved: Art for the 80's" invitation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Exhibition - Scot Borofsky: Collage Cityscape - Oil Landscape" flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Blast" zine - September, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bridge Between Hispanic and American Art - exhibit card, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Land of 1000 Galleries" exhibit card, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Young American Painters: Barry Stevens" exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Scot Borofsky: Collage Painting" at Seventeenth Street Gallery - exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - REDTAPE Benefit - exhibit card, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Scot Borofsky at Life Cafe" cards, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Pintores de Nueva York" exhibit in Mexico - card, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Pyramid Gallery group show - exhibit card, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Big Deal(s) - group exhibit card, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "The New Generation" exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Mask and Figures - group exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Scot Borofsky" exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Beyond Boundaries: A World Mosaic" exhibit card, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Scot Borofsky: Collage Construction" at Life Cafe - exhibit card, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Scot Borofsky: Recent Paintings and Sculpture" at Mokotoff Gallery - card, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Garbaggio" exhibit card, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "One Man Show of Paintings by Scot Borofsky" program, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "5 Windham County Artists" program, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Leisure Weekly" with Borofsky drawing on front page, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Scot Borofsky's 911 Series" exhibit card, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "New Paintings by Scot Borofsky" exhibit card, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series III: Media
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - "Mixed Blood", 1985; ID: 346.0001 (Box 1, Media ID: 346.0001)
    Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Original format: VHS Duration: 98 minutes Director: Paul Morrisey